¬ Localised file for campaign descriptions
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TITLE}Velká kampaň
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_TITLE}Mordor
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_DESCR}The Witch-King of Angmar \n\n\n\nSauron was originally a mere servant, the Lieutenant of Morgoth. After the defeat of his master at the end of the First Age, he hid himself in a dark place in Middle Earth, only to emerge 500 years later as Annatar, supposedly as an emissary of the Valar. His beautiful visage and cunning performance seduced the Elves of Eregion. They crafted the rings of power, desiring to sustain all things. Yet in secret, he secretly forged a ring through which he could dominate all the others. However, the elves deduced his plan immediately and took off the rings. Furious, Sauron unleashed the armies he had been building in the black land of Mordor, thus initiating the of War of Elves and Sauron. The slaughter was terrible, with the lands west of the Anduin being completely overrun by his hordes of orcs. Yet Gil-Galad and his elven subjects did not submit, and with the aid of a powerful Númenórean host, his forces were decimated and forced to retreat back to Mordor.\n\nFrom then on Sauron would be the Dark Lord of Mordor. Barad-Dur would finally be completed, it serving as the citadel from which he would direct his armies of Orcs and Trolls. The evil men to the south and east would come under his dominion as their God-King. He was at the height of his power. Ar-Pharazôn the Golden, last and strongest of the kings of Numenor, believed it was right to rule Middle Earth though. He set sail with a vast host and cornered Sauron, whose army had deserted him when faced the glory of Man. In a humiliating display, he surrendered to Ar-Pharazon, who took him as a captive. Yet Sauron managed to reverse his situation and even acheive the impossible: the corruption and destruction of Numenor.\n\nSauron was furious when he first learned of the Kingdoms in Exile. He ordered an attack upon these kingdoms, seeking to wipe out the last vestiges of Numenor. Yet his blow would prove too hasty. His armies were routed by an alliance of Elves and Men; Barad-Dur itself was besieged. There the valour of men and the shapness of a sword would prove to be his downfall. Once again he fled into the deep shadows.\n\nYet all this is in the past. Gondor lies withered like the tree she fights for. Arnor lies dead, killed by his faithful servant while he was exiled. The Elves are a laughable remant of their former glory. The Dwarves stew in their own muck deep in the mountains. NOW is the time for the final conquest of Middle Earth. NOW is the time when Sauron will smother the Earth in shadow. For against the power of the Dark Lord of Mordor, there is no hope of victory.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TEUTONIC_ORDER_TITLE}Mordor
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TEUTONIC_ORDER_DESCR}Zástupka
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_IRELAND_TITLE}Ireland
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_IRELAND_DESCR}Placeholder
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORWAY_TITLE}Norway
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_NORWAY_DESCR}Placeholder
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_TITLE}Dol
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_DESCR}King Bard the Bowman \n\n\n\nThe valley of Dale lies directly south of the Lonely Mountain and overlooks the Long Lake. It was populated in the Third Age, and perhaps earlier, by tribes of Northmen who originally inhabited the entire region between the rivers Celdiun and Carnen. The city itself was founded in 2590 and flourished through trade with the wealthy Dwarves of Erebor.\n\nBut the dragon Smaug, attracted by the treasures of Erebor, attacked the Dwarven kingdom in 2770, destroying it and leaving Dale parched and ruined. The survivors fled south and lived amongst the Lake-men of Esgaroth, also known as “Lake-town”. In 2941 the men of Dale, allied with the Dwarves and Elves, successfully drove back an army of orcs and wolves at the Battle of Five Armies. In the same year, Bard the Bowman, exiled heir to the throne of Dale, shot Smaug with a single arrow as it attacked Lake-town, defeating the dragon at last. The people of Dale returned home and begun rebuilding their once prosperous city, with Bard – the Dragonslayer – chosen as their new leader and King.\n\nFinally free from the threat of Smaug, Dale and Lake-town, united under Bard, are steadily regaining their former strength. Perhaps it would be wise to pursue the orcs, attacking their strongholds in the Misty Mountains. The Dwarves of Erebor, our steadfast allies, also harbour a great dislike for them; they will surely join our cause. Another course of action would be to turn to the East and reclaim the lands of our ancestors from the wild and barbaric Easterlings.\n\nDale’s armies consist of militia and knights from the city as well as Northmen mercenaries from surrounding lands. Weapons and armour bought from Erebor ensure only the best quality, and the bowmen of Dale are known for their skill, discipline and courage. 
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_TITLE}Isengard
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_DESCR}Saruman \n\n\n\nIsengard is a single stronghold, built by Numenorians after the fall of their kingdom and originally named Agrenost, 'the Iron Fortress'. Its fortifications consist of a series of strong ringwalls with the tower of Orthanc in the centre. Under Gondor it became known as Orthanc which means "Mount Fang" in Sindarin. Orthanc housed one of the palantíri of the South Kingdom, and was guarded by a royal warden.\n\nIn the early days of the Stewards, the tower was locked and its keys taken to Minas Tirith. When Isengard fell to the Dunlendings in T.A. 2710 they were unable to enter the tower. When Beren, Steward of Gondor, gave Isengard to the wizard Saruman, in the year 2759, he also gave him the keys to Orthanc.\n\nInitially Saruman, uncorrupted, was a good ally to Rohan, but as his mind became shadowed by the power of Sauron, his will was fixed on finding the One Ring. Spies of Saruman were searching for the One Ring near the Anduin, so Isengard was the perfect base for his operations. Saruman has not been idle, in an unprecedented act of evil he has conspired to create Uruk-Hai. These vile creatures are part orcs, part men, unaffected by sunlight and fanatically obedient. The men in question are children of Rohan, abducted by force for Saruman’s foul experiments. Harnessing the sight of the palantir and having gone unsuspected for so long, he has gained news of the One Ring and from his stronghold could strike anywhere.\n\nAcquiring the favour of the wild men of Dunland, who hate the Rohirrim, he has swelled his armies with vast numbers. Saruman has even developed regiments of pikemen and wargriders specifically to counter the might of neighbouring Rohan. Isengard’s hordes are armed with bows, crossbows, yatahans, swords and spears and all manner of arms and armour that the smoldering forges and foundries of Isengard can churn out. The wheels of a black industry are grinding against not only Rohan but all the Free Peoples of Middle-earth.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HRE_TITLE}Orcs of the Misty Mountains
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HRE_DESCR}High Chieftain Uglag \n\n\n\nUpon the defeat of Morgoth by the hosts of the Valar, the many creatures bred by Morgoth in the pits of Angband were hunted down and destroyed. Those who escaped the forces of the West fled deep into the dark places of the world, awaiting their time for vengeance.\n\nMany orcs of Morgoth's host fled into the roots of the Misty Mountains, where no other power could hunt them.There they remained throughout the Second Age, nursing their hatred and waiting for the time to strike. Throughout the Third Age these Orcs and Goblins fought against the Dwarves in a great war, ending in the Battle of Nanduhirion, where Dáin Ironfoot slew Azog, the great Orc-chieftain of Moria. What these Orcs lack in individual valor they more than make up for in numbers, using the horde as an alternative to single combat.\n\nNow, as the Third Age wanes, perhaps that time has come. In 2941 TA, Bolg, son of Azog, led the Orcs against the combined might of Elves, Dwarves, and Men in the Battle of Five Armies. Their defeat served only to strengthen their resolve and lead them to their ultimate goal: to destroy the Free Peoples of Middle-earth.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_TITLE}Vznešení elfové
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_DESCR}High-King Elrond \n\n\n\nIn the final years of the First Age, when the conquest of Beleriand by Morgoth was all but complete, the Valar sent a great host to defeat the Dark Lord once and for all. Their victory, however, was dearly-won, for in the violence and tumult of the War of Wrath, the lands of Beleriand were destroyed and lost beneath the waves of the sea. Of the Noldor who survived and the Sindar who followed them, those who yet desired to remain in Middle-earth followed Ereinion Gil-galad to Lindon. There, they built Mithlond, the Gray Havens, and the twin harbors of Forlond and Harlond.\n\nOthers of the Noldor, led by Celebrimbor, continued eastward into Eriador and established the realm of Eregion. It was here that Sauron, lieutenant of Morgoth, approached the elves in disguise. Under his deceitful guidance, the elves crafted the Rings of Power, of which the Three Rings of the Elves were the fairest and greatest. But when Sauron crafted in secret the One Ring to dominate all of the other Rings of Power, the elves perceived his true nature and hid away the Three. Realizing that he no longer held sway over the elves, Sauron moved quickly, destroying Eregion and slaying Celebrimbor. Those who survived the fall of Eregion fled to the east, where -- under the leadership of Elrond -- they established the refuge of Imladris, Rivendell, in the foothills of the Misty Mountains.\n\nWith the assistance of men from Númenór, the elves were able to drive Sauron back to Mordor, andfter a seven-year siege upon the fortress of Barad-dûr, the Last Alliance of Elves and Men were able to defeat him and scatter his forces. However, the power of the Noldor was greatly diminished. Many, including Gil-galad their king, were slain, and most of those who survived decided to end their long exile in Middle-earth and return to the Undying Lands across the sea.\n\nToday, the realms of Mithlond and Imladris have but a whisper of their old glory, and they no longer have the strength or numbers to march openly again against the resurgent power of Mordor. Yet the valor of the elves has not diminished through all the long ages of Middle-earth, and by their vigilance the lands east of the Misty Mountains are yet kept safe from the shadows growing again in the East. 
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_TITLE}Rhůn
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_DESCR}Chieftain Borthand \n\n\n\nEasterlings are the nomadic peoples that inhabit the little-known eastern lands of Middle-earth, from beyond the Sea of Rhûn in the east to as far west as Rhovanion. These various different folks and tribes are united only in their wild and cruel nature, and their hatred for the West, particularly the Númenóreans and their descendants.\n\nOver the years, the Easterlings have been a constant foe of the Free Peoples, pledging allegiance to both the Dark Lords: first Morgoth, and later his disciple, Sauron. It was thanks to the treacherous Ulfang the Black, who betrayed the Sons of Fëanor, that Morgoth saw victory at the the Battle of Unnumbered Tears during the First Age. Later, in the Third Age, Easterling tribes continuously attacked the Kingdom of Gondor. Amongst them, the fierce Balchoth and the Wainriders gained renown in the West. The series of successful raids ended after Gondor formed an alliance with the Rohirrim and drove the Easterling forces from their realms.\n\nWeakened and separated, the Easterling tribes require a strong and clever Chieftain to unite them, and to carry out the Dark Lord’s plans. The Free Peoples of Middle-earth are to be destroyed; to the West, Rohan and Gondor shall pay for their previous victories and to the North, the rich cities of Erebor and Dale need to be humbled.\n\nEasterling armies are broad and varied. Included are the heavy infantry of Rhûn, the great chariots of the Wainriders, the notorious Balchoth raiders, Hazga archers and from Khand come the Variags – a savage race of warrior people, known for their brutal cavalry. 
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_TITLE}Gondor
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_DESCR}Steward Denethor II\n\n\n\nGondor, the Southern Kingdom of the Númenóreans – founded in the Second Age by Elendil, and ruled by his sons Isildur and Anárion. After the War of the Last Alliance, in which both Elendil and Anárion were lost, and the death of Isildur by an Orc ambush, the throne fell to Anárion's son Meneldil. Gondor prospered for many decades under the rule of Anárion’s line, and became the most powerful kingdom in the land, expanding its borders and conquering parts of Harad and Rhûn.\n\nBut after the return of Sauron darkness fell upon Gondor. Civil war, plague and Easterling expansions gravely weakened the once powerful Kingdom. Lands were lost to the South and East; the cities of Osgiliath and Ithilien were devasted; the tower of Minas Ithil was captured by the Nazgûl, and thereafter known as Minas Morgul. Eärnur, last King of Gondor, fell at the hands of the Witch-king, and Gondor fell into the hands of Stewards. Many years of war and instability followed. Eventually, Steward Cirion called on the Éothéod, a tribe of Northmen, for aid, and the enemy was successfully driven back. As a reward, he granted Gondor’s new allies the province of Calenardhon, where they founded the Kingdom of Rohan.\n\nNow Steward Ecthelion II rules in Gondor, and he must strengthen his realm against the threat of Mordor and its allies: the Haradrim and the Easterlings. The Pirates of Umbar cause a further threat, pillaging the Kingdom’s southern coasts. Gondor’s stability and pride hangs in the balance.\n\nThe bulk of Gondor’s army is made up of well-trained infantry and the less-experienced provincial militia. Higher ranking troops include the Fountain Guard and Ithilien archers. However, Gondor’s pride truly lies in their cavalry – few in numbers but powerful knights of Minas Tirith and Dol Amroth, capable of breaking any enemy formation. 
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_TITLE}Rohan
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_DESCR}King Thengel \n\n\n\nThe Kingdom of Rohan was established in the Third Age, when the cavalry forces of the Kingdom of Rhovanion were destroyed by Easterlings and forced to flee beyond Greenwood the Great. These Horse People of Northmen called themselves Éothéod. They settled for some time to the north of the Anduin. In time Cirion, Steward of Gondor, called upon these descendants of Rhovanion, old allies of Gondor, for aid against the Balchoth.\n\nThus in 2510 of the Third Age, the Éothéod King Eorl the Young led his horsemen in the Battle of the Field of Celebrant, and after defeating the enemy Cirion asked the Éothéod to watch over the depopulated province of Calenardhon. The Éothéod henceforth called themselves Eorlingas or "followers of Eorl", but in Sindarin they became known as the Rohirrim, or Horse-lords, and their country became known as Rohan, the Riddermark.\n\nEorl, first King of the Mark built his capital at Aldburg in the Folde. It was Rohan's second King, Brego son of Eorl, who then established a stronghold on the green hill of Edoras at the foot of the White Mountains in the south of the Mark. At its heart stands Meduseld, the Golden Hall.\n\nDuring the time of king Helm Hammerhand around 2750, men from Dunland in the north had become hateful of the new settlers at their southern borders, who had driven them to poor lands in the hills. Now the Dunlendings came against Rohan in force under Freca and Wulf, besieging Edoras twice in four years. Pirates from Umbar were raiding Gondor and so it was unable to aid its ally in the north. The Rohirrim were forced to retreat to the fortresses of the Hornburg and Dunharrow.\n\nDuring the desperate fighting over a long winter King Helm was slain and all his sons, thus a new line of Rohirrim kings was born in Helm’s nephew – Frealaf Hildeson. Gondor eventually arrived in the spring and liberated the Riddermark from the Dunlendings.\n\nFor a time there was peace by since Saruman has settled in Isengard the folk have begun to wonder whether the terrifying wizard has had some hand in the woes that have beset the Riddermark. Dunlendings stir once more and strange creatures raiding the outer hamlets in the north have been seen bearing the dreaded White Hand of the wizard himself.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_TITLE}Denmark
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_TITLE}Eriador
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_DESCR}King Aragorn Elessar \n\n\n\nThe lands between the Misty Mountains and the Blue Mountains are named Eriador. In the north it is bordered by the frozen bay of Forochel and in the south by the White Mountains. Such natural defences have at times allowed the land to prosper, but it has not always been peaceful.\n\nFor in the year 3320 of the Second Age, Elendil established the Northern kingdom of Numenorians - Arnor. Elendil built many settlements here – Amnnuminas the great capital of Arnor, and fortresses such as Fornost, Amon Sul and Tarbad. There was also the high tower of Elostirion in which one of the great treasures of Middle-earth was kept the great Palantir.. Sauron hated the Dúnedain Numenorians and sought to destroy them. In the war of the Last Alliance, the Dark Lord’s forces were defeated but leaders of the Alliance against him - Elendil and Gil-galad were killed in the fighting. Isildur - son of Elendil was himself the bane of the Dark Lord and it was he that took up the One Ring. When Elendil fell and the One Ring was lost, his son Valandil became king. After the Disaster of the Gladden Fields, Arnor began its slow decline. While Gondor rose in power, Arnor waned.\n\nAfter the death of its tenth king, Eärendur, in T.A. 861, Arnor was shaken by civil war between the three sons of Eärendur. The eldest son, Amlaith, claimed Kingship over all Arnor but was reduced to only ruling the region of Arthedain as his kingdom, while the other sons founded the kingdoms of Cardolan and Rhudaur. The former capital, Annúminas, became depopulated and fell into ruin. This marked the start of the decline of the Northern Dúnedain.\n\nThe three kingdoms had frequent border skirmishes over boundary disputes, but the relationship of Arthedain and Cardolan remained relatively peaceful. However, Rhudaur was unfriendly towards the two other successor states, and took part in a bitter conflict with Cardolan over the tower of Amon Sûl and the palantír associated with the tower. Around T.A. 1300, an evil power, the Witch-king, arose in the mountains of the North East, where he founded Angmar. It was later revealed he was the leader of the Nazgûl.\n\nIn 1974 the Witch-king destroyed Fornost and with it the last of Dunedain here. One year later Angmar was defeated by Gondor and Elves but northern Kingdom of Numenorians was lost. Only a part of dunedain leading by Aradart - descendant of Isildur survived. Most of Eriador people died in wars and in time of Great Plague, last of the Dúnedain. Although some still wander in the wilderness, to all intents and purposes, Eriador has been ever since a kingdom without a king, or at least a king who would show himself to the Shadow.\n\nBut as the echoes of Sauron whisper in the world, the rallying cry has risen in the Free Lands. Aragorn II, son of Arathorn, is the last of the great Dúnedain and the burdened king of Eriador. Aragorn would seek to reforge not only the alliance of men and Elves, but also the kingdoms of Arnor reunited into a mighty whole, and perhaps even the shards of Narsil.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_TITLE}Dwarves
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_DESCR}King Dain \n\n\n\nAfter the destruction of the great Dwarven settlements of Nogrod and Belegost at the end of First Age, and the capturing of Khazad-dûm by the Balrog in 1980, the Dwarves fell into decay. Constant warring with Dragons and Orcs saw the loss of settlements in the Grey Mountains and Erebor. The nine-year-long War of the Dwarves and the Orcs, culminating in the bloody Battle of Azanulbizar, saw the eventual defeat of the Orcs, but brought with it severe repercussions, threatening the Dwarves’ very existence.\n\nOnly in the year 2941, after Bard the Bowman slew the dragon Smaug, did the Dwarves at last regain hope. Allying with the Men of Dale and Mirkwood Elves, they won the Battle of Five Armies, reclaiming the Lonely Mountain. Dwarves of the Iron Hills, led by Dáin Ironfoot, resettled Erebor and started the tiresome resurrection of a tattered nation.\n\nWith the Northern Goblins weak and scattered, it is a great opportunity to regain native lands. Moreover Balin, one of the great Dwarven princes, has sworn to return to Khazad-dûm and muster troops for the campaign to reclaim Moria. And to the South, the Men of Dale have proven to be our loyal allies; we can always count on them for help.\n\nDwarven armies consist mostly of heavy infantry. Armed with axes and battle-hammers, they are deadly at short range. When it comes to armour, the Dwarves’ skill in forging steel and mithril is unmatched. Further, the Dwarven reputation as master engineers allows them some of the finest siege weapons, and gives them access to the crossbow. Their alliance with Dale allows them to hire some basic Northman units, making up for their lack of cavalry.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_TITLE}Poland
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_TITLE}Byzantium
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_TITLE}Hungary
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_TITLE}Russia
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AZTECS_TITLE}The Aztecs
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_AZTECS_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_TITLE}Harad
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_DESCR}Chieftain Khuzaymah \n\n\n\nFor the lands beyond the River Harnen the men of Gondor give no name other than Harad -- the South -- and to the proud and warlike people who dwell there they give no label other than Haradrim -- Men of the South. These are descendants of men who fell under the sway of Morgoth during the First Age and who rallied to the banners of Sauron in the Second Age.\n\nLong have the Haradrim been at odds with the men of Gondor, and often have the borders between the two realms been redrawn due to war and conquest. In the year 1050 of the Third Age, King Ciryaher utterly vanquished the armies of the Haradrim and compelled their kings to accept the authority of Gondor, a feat that won him the name Hyarmendacil -- Victor of the South.\n\nThe supremacy of Gondor was short-lived, however, for barely four centuries later, a dispute over succession threw Gondor into civil war. As a result of the Kin-strife, the sons of Castamir the Usurper departed Gondor with the bulk of the fleet anchored at Pelargir and established themselves in the ancient Númenórian haven of Umbar. What hold Gondor held over the Haradrim was lost, and many alliances were forged between the rebels -- now known as the Corsairs of Umbar -- and the men of Harad. In the years since, the two peoples have perpetuated war against Gondor, terrorizing the coasts and contesting control over the lands of southern territories of Harondor.\n\nWhile the men who march under the serpent banner of Harad cannot hope to match the craft of Gondor in the smithing of weapons and armor, the armies of Harad are vast, their spears sharp, and their steeds swift. Furthermore, in the lands to the north, rumors abound of mûmakil, great tusked beasts of war coaxed from the jungles of the Far Harad that are all but unstoppable in battle. With such weapons at their disposal and allied with the forces of Mordor resurgent the Haradrim may yet see final triumph over their ancient foe to the north.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_TITLE}Orcs of Gundabad
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_DESCR}Chieftain Gorduf \n\n\n\nThe Orcs of Gundabad, unlike their southern mountain kin, are more organised and are a force to be feared. Ever since the fall of Morgoth in the First Age, the Orcs have bred and lived in the region surrounding Gundabad and throughout the northern mountains including the Ettenmoors, the Mountains of Angmar and Ered Mithrim (The Grey Mountains).\nIn 1300 TA, a great Numenorian Sorceror, later known as the Witch King of Angmar, appeared in the region around Angmar and united the Orcs, Trolls, Wicked Men and the other creatures that dwelt there. Most of the Witch King's manpower came from the mountain dwellers of Gundabad which was a great mountain at the very top of the Misty Mountain range. When Arnor was destroyed in 1975 TA, the Orcs of Gundabad celebrated the destruction of their mortal enemies and began the pillaging of the undefended citizens of Eriador. However, a Gondorian Army, with the Elves of Lindon, Rivendell and the remnants of Arnor, defeated the Witch King at Fornost. Angmar was soon laid to waste and most of the Orcs were destroyed, Gundabad remained untouched, although its power was shattered.\nThis was not the end of Gundabad's troubles. In 1977, two years after the loss of Angmar, the Eotheod settled in the northern Anduin and destroyed all remnants of Angmar in the mountains. Gundabad was beyond recovery, but barely defended their lands. New hope came in 1981 when the Dwarves of Khazad-Dum were driven from the Misty Mountains by a Balrog. When Sauron was driven from Dol Guldur in 2063, the Free Peoples of Middle Earth once again had dominance of the northern lands and Gundabad's existance was once again threatened. 200 years later, many Dwarves migrated north from Erebor to the Grey Mountains and immediately went to war with expanding clans of Orcs living there. Gundabad reacted with strength and the next 200 years were a bloody battle fought over the dominance of the Grey Mountains. In 2480, Sauron peopled Moria with his creatures and began fortifying the Misty Mountains, blocking Eriador from the people of the Wilderlands.\nThe fortune of Gundabad began to turn for the better by the end of the 26th century of the Third Age. Dragons came down from the Northern Wastes and continously attacked the Dwarven colonies in the Grey Mountains, and in 2589, the great Dwarven lord, Dain I, was slain by one and the next year his son and his brother returned south to Erebor, one leaving for the Iron Hills. With them went most of the Dwarves, but a remnant kept mining and fighting there, though only a slight annoyance to Gundabad over the next 200 years.\nIn 2740, judging their strength to be powerful enough, Gundabad launched an invasion on Eriador. However, this went badly for the Orcs and in 2746, a great Hobbit warrior defeated an Orc Army in the North Farthing and personally slew their chieftain. In 2770, the Dwarves were driven out of Erebor by a Dragon known as Smaug, giving the Orcs of Gundabad complete supremacy over the Northern Ranges. However, this started a chain of events which caused the Dwarves of Middle Earth to muster their armies and begin a war of vengeance upon the Orcs of the Misty Mountains. In 2793, the War of the Dwarves and Orcs began in 2793 which resulted in the destruction of the Orcs. Gundabad fell late in the war and the Orc population was completely destroyed. When the great Orc cheiftan named Azog fell at Nanduhirion, the Dwarven Armies were victorious and dispersed, leaving the despaired survivors of Gundabad to slowly recolonise.\nOver the next two hundred years, Gundabad remained relatively quiet and had little to do with the events in Middle Earth...until now.
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_TITLE}The Dark Lord of Mordor
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_TITLE}Silvan Elves
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_DESCR}King Thranduil \n\n\n\nDoriath, the Hidden Kingdom, was the greatest of the Sindarin realms in Beleriand. For many long years, it flourished under the rule of Elu Thingol and Melian his queen, but during the Wars of Beleriand it was destroyed, sacked first by treacherous dwarves and later by the jealous Sons of Fëanor. Many of those who survived the fall of the realm fled east past the towering peaks of the Hithaeglir into lands where the Tawarwaith -- Silvan elves long sundered from the elves of Beleriand -- dwelled.\n\nBeing a rustic people lesser in wisdom than the Sindar, the Silvan elves accepted the Sindar as their lords. Under the guidance of Amdír and Oropher, the realms of Lindórinand and Eryn Lasgalen were established, and for many years the elves lived in peace. Peace, however, was not to last, for the rising power of Mordor forced the Silvan elves and their Sindarin princes to take up arms. During the Last Alliance of Elves and Men, Amdír and Oropher, along with their sons Amroth and Thranduil, heeded the call Gil-galad and led great hosts to battle. Sauron was defeated, but at great cost -- both Amdír and Oropher were slain, along with most of their armies.\n\nHis heart filled with disquiet and disillusionment, Thranduil led his people northwards, where he established his Woodland Realm and delved an underground fortress in the style of Menegroth in Doriath. In Lindórinand, now known as Lothlórien, Amroth took over the lordship of his father's kingdom. After Amroth was lost at sea searching for his beloved, the Silvan maiden Nimrodel, Celeborn and Galadriel took up the guardianship of the realm, fortifying it against the resurgent power of Mordor.\n\nUnder the guidance of the Lord and Lady of the Wood, the realm of Lothlórien shines in defiance of the shadow growing in the East, a fortress against the encroaching darkness. And while the Silvan elves of Lórien and the Woodland Realm may be ill-equipped in arms and armor when compared to their western kin, they are hardy and valiant warriors whose skill with the bow is unmatched and whose hatred of Sauron runs deep. 
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_TITLE}The Timurids
{IMPERIAL_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{NORMAN_PROLOGUE_NORMANS_TITLE}The Norman Conquest
{NORMAN_PROLOGUE_NORMANS_DESCR}Lead William the Conqueror and his Norman army to victory at the Battle of Hastings, then defeat the Saxons for control of the English throne. \n\nEdward the Confessor's death saw England fall into a bitter power struggle. With no heirs to the English throne, three competing powers arose to stake their claim. Harold Godwinson was quick to seize power, with the support of the English Witan. However, the King of Norway, Harald Hardrada, felt the land his birthright and sailed from the North. The two kings clashed at Stamford Bridge in a bloody battle.\n\nBut the late King Edward had promised the throne to the Duke of Normandy, who sought Papal blessing to launch an invasion of his own.
{NORMAN_PROLOGUE_TITLE}The Norman Conquest
¬
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_TITLE}The Fellowship Campaign
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_TITLE}Mordor
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_ENGLAND_DESCR}The Witch-King of Angmar \n\n\n\nSauron was originally a mere servant, the Lieutenant of Morgoth. After the defeat of his master at the end of the First Age, he hid himself in a dark place in Middle Earth, only to emerge 500 years later as Annatar, supposedly as an emissary of the Valar. His beautiful visage and cunning performance seduced the Elves of Eregion. They crafted the rings of power, desiring to sustain all things. Yet in secret, he secretly forged a ring through which he could dominate all the others. However, the elves deduced his plan immediately and took off the rings. Furious, Sauron unleashed the armies he had been building in the black land of Mordor, thus initiating the of War of Elves and Sauron. The slaughter was terrible, with the lands west of the Anduin being completely overrun by his hordes of orcs. Yet Gil-Galad and his elven subjects did not submit, and with the aid of a powerful Númenórean host, his forces were decimated and forced to retreat back to Mordor.\n\nFrom then on Sauron would be the Dark Lord of Mordor. Barad-Dur would finally be completed, it serving as the citadel from which he would direct his armies of Orcs and Trolls. The evil men to the south and east would come under his dominion as their God-King. He was at the height of his power. Ar-Pharazôn the Golden, last and strongest of the kings of Numenor, believed it was right to rule Middle Earth though. He set sail with a vast host and cornered Sauron, whose army had deserted him when faced the glory of Man. In a humiliating display, he surrendered to Ar-Pharazon, who took him as a captive. Yet Sauron managed to reverse his situation and even acheive the impossible: the corruption and destruction of Numenor.\n\nSauron was furious when he first learned of the Kingdoms in Exile. He ordered an attack upon these kingdoms, seeking to wipe out the last vestiges of Numenor. Yet his blow would prove too hasty. His armies were routed by an alliance of Elves and Men; Barad-Dur itself was besieged. There the valour of men and the shapness of a sword would prove to be his downfall. Once again he fled into the deep shadows.\n\nYet all this is in the past. Gondor lies withered like the tree she fights for. Arnor lies dead, killed by his faithful servant while he was exiled. The Elves are a laughable remant of their former glory. The Dwarves stew in their own muck deep in the mountains. NOW is the time for the final conquest of Middle Earth. NOW is the time when Sauron will smother the Earth in shadow. For against the power of the Dark Lord of Mordor, there is no hope of victory.
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_TEUTONIC_ORDER_TITLE}Mordor
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_TEUTONIC_ORDER_DESCR}Placeholder
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_IRELAND_TITLE}Ireland
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_IRELAND_DESCR}Placeholder
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_NORWAY_TITLE}Norway
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_NORWAY_DESCR}Placeholder
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_TITLE}Dale
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_SCOTLAND_DESCR}King Bard the Bowman \n\n\n\nThe valley of Dale lies directly south of the Lonely Mountain and overlooks the Long Lake. It was populated in the Third Age, and perhaps earlier, by tribes of Northmen who originally inhabited the entire region between the rivers Celdiun and Carnen. The city itself was founded in 2590 and flourished through trade with the wealthy Dwarves of Erebor.\n\nBut the dragon Smaug, attracted by the treasures of Erebor, attacked the Dwarven kingdom in 2770, destroying it and leaving Dale parched and ruined. The survivors fled south and lived amongst the Lake-men of Esgaroth, also known as “Lake-town”. In 2941 the men of Dale, allied with the Dwarves and Elves, successfully drove back an army of orcs and wolves at the Battle of Five Armies. In the same year, Bard the Bowman, exiled heir to the throne of Dale, shot Smaug with a single arrow as it attacked Lake-town, defeating the dragon at last. The people of Dale returned home and begun rebuilding their once prosperous city, with Bard – the Dragonslayer – chosen as their new leader and King.\n\nFinally free from the threat of Smaug, Dale and Lake-town, united under Bard, are steadily regaining their former strength. Perhaps it would be wise to pursue the orcs, attacking their strongholds in the Misty Mountains. The Dwarves of Erebor, our steadfast allies, also harbour a great dislike for them; they will surely join our cause. Another course of action would be to turn to the East and reclaim the lands of our ancestors from the wild and barbaric Easterlings.\n\nDale’s armies consist of militia and knights from the city as well as Northmen mercenaries from surrounding lands. Weapons and armour bought from Erebor ensure only the best quality, and the bowmen of Dale are known for their skill, discipline and courage. 
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_TITLE}Isengard
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_FRANCE_DESCR}Chieftain Ugluk \n\n\n\nIsengard is a single stronghold, built by Numenorians after the fall of their kingdom and originally named Agrenost, 'the Iron Fortress'. Its fortifications consist of a series of strong ringwalls with the tower of Orthanc in the centre. Under Gondor it became known as Orthanc which means "Mount Fang" in Sindarin. Orthanc housed one of the palantíri of the South Kingdom, and was guarded by a royal warden.\n\nIn the early days of the Stewards, the tower was locked and its keys taken to Minas Tirith. When Isengard fell to the Dunlendings in T.A. 2710 they were unable to enter the tower. When Beren, Steward of Gondor, gave Isengard to the wizard Saruman, in the year 2759, he also gave him the keys to Orthanc.\n\nInitially Saruman, uncorrupted, was a good ally to Rohan, but as his mind became shadowed by the power of Sauron, his will was fixed on finding the One Ring. Spies of Saruman were searching for the One Ring near the Anduin, so Isengard was the perfect base for his operations. Saruman has not been idle, in an unprecedented act of evil he has conspired to create Uruk-Hai. These vile creatures are part orcs, part men, unaffected by sunlight and fanatically obedient. The men in question are children of Rohan, abducted by force for Saruman’s foul experiments. Harnessing the sight of the palantir and having gone unsuspected for so long, he has gained news of the One Ring and from his stronghold could strike anywhere.\n\nAcquiring the favour of the wild men of Dunland, who hate the Rohirrim, he has swelled his armies with vast numbers. Saruman has even developed regiments of pikemen and wargriders specifically to counter the might of neighbouring Rohan. Isengard’s hordes are armed with bows, crossbows, yatahans, swords and spears and all manner of arms and armour that the smoldering forges and foundries of Isengard can churn out. The wheels of a black industry are grinding against not only Rohan but all the Free Peoples of Middle-earth.
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_HRE_TITLE}Orcs of the Misty Mountains
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_HRE_DESCR}High Chieftain Uglag \n\n\n\nUpon the defeat of Morgoth by the hosts of the Valar, the many creatures bred by Morgoth in the pits of Angband were hunted down and destroyed. Those who escaped the forces of the West fled deep into the dark places of the world, awaiting their time for vengeance.\n\nMany orcs of Morgoth's host fled into the roots of the Misty Mountains, where no other power could hunt them.There they remained throughout the Second Age, nursing their hatred and waiting for the time to strike. Throughout the Third Age these Orcs and Goblins fought against the Dwarves in a great war, ending in the Battle of Nanduhirion, where Dáin Ironfoot slew Azog, the great Orc-chieftain of Moria. What these Orcs lack in individual valor they more than make up for in numbers, using the horde as an alternative to single combat.\n\nNow, as the Third Age wanes, perhaps that time has come. In 2941 TA, Bolg, son of Azog, led the Orcs against the combined might of Elves, Dwarves, and Men in the Battle of Five Armies. Their defeat served only to strengthen their resolve and lead them to their ultimate goal: to destroy the Free Peoples of Middle-earth.
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_TITLE}High Elves
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_EGYPT_DESCR}High-King Elrond \n\n\n\nIn the final years of the First Age, when the conquest of Beleriand by Morgoth was all but complete, the Valar sent a great host to defeat the Dark Lord once and for all. Their victory, however, was dearly-won, for in the violence and tumult of the War of Wrath, the lands of Beleriand were destroyed and lost beneath the waves of the sea. Of the Noldor who survived and the Sindar who followed them, those who yet desired to remain in Middle-earth followed Ereinion Gil-galad to Lindon. There, they built Mithlond, the Gray Havens, and the twin harbors of Forlond and Harlond.\n\nOthers of the Noldor, led by Celebrimbor, continued eastward into Eriador and established the realm of Eregion. It was here that Sauron, lieutenant of Morgoth, approached the elves in disguise. Under his deceitful guidance, the elves crafted the Rings of Power, of which the Three Rings of the Elves were the fairest and greatest. But when Sauron crafted in secret the One Ring to dominate all of the other Rings of Power, the elves perceived his true nature and hid away the Three. Realizing that he no longer held sway over the elves, Sauron moved quickly, destroying Eregion and slaying Celebrimbor. Those who survived the fall of Eregion fled to the east, where -- under the leadership of Elrond -- they established the refuge of Imladris, Rivendell, in the foothills of the Misty Mountains.\n\nWith the assistance of men from Númenór, the elves were able to drive Sauron back to Mordor, andfter a seven-year siege upon the fortress of Barad-dûr, the Last Alliance of Elves and Men were able to defeat him and scatter his forces. However, the power of the Noldor was greatly diminished. Many, including Gil-galad their king, were slain, and most of those who survived decided to end their long exile in Middle-earth and return to the Undying Lands across the sea.\n\nToday, the realms of Mithlond and Imladris have but a whisper of their old glory, and they no longer have the strength or numbers to march openly again against the resurgent power of Mordor. Yet the valor of the elves has not diminished through all the long ages of Middle-earth, and by their vigilance the lands east of the Misty Mountains are yet kept safe from the shadows growing again in the East. 
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_TITLE}Rhûn
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_VENICE_DESCR}Chieftain Borthand \n\n\n\nEasterlings are the nomadic peoples that inhabit the little-known eastern lands of Middle-earth, from beyond the Sea of Rhûn in the east to as far west as Rhovanion. These various different folks and tribes are united only in their wild and cruel nature, and their hatred for the West, particularly the Númenóreans and their descendants.\n\nOver the years, the Easterlings have been a constant foe of the Free Peoples, pledging allegiance to both the Dark Lords: first Morgoth, and later his disciple, Sauron. It was thanks to the treacherous Ulfang the Black, who betrayed the Sons of Fëanor, that Morgoth saw victory at the the Battle of Unnumbered Tears during the First Age. Later, in the Third Age, Easterling tribes continuously attacked the Kingdom of Gondor. Amongst them, the fierce Balchoth and the Wainriders gained renown in the West. The series of successful raids ended after Gondor formed an alliance with the Rohirrim and drove the Easterling forces from their realms.\n\nWeakened and separated, the Easterling tribes require a strong and clever Chieftain to unite them, and to carry out the Dark Lord’s plans. The Free Peoples of Middle-earth are to be destroyed; to the West, Rohan and Gondor shall pay for their previous victories and to the North, the rich cities of Erebor and Dale need to be humbled.\n\nEasterling armies are broad and varied. Included are the heavy infantry of Rhûn, the great chariots of the Wainriders, the notorious Balchoth raiders, Hazga archers and from Khand come the Variags – a savage race of warrior people, known for their brutal cavalry. 
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_TITLE}Gondor
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_SICILY_DESCR}Steward Denethor II\n\n\n\nGondor, the Southern Kingdom of the Númenóreans – founded in the Second Age by Elendil, and ruled by his sons Isildur and Anárion. After the War of the Last Alliance, in which both Elendil and Anárion were lost, and the death of Isildur by an Orc ambush, the throne fell to Anárion's son Meneldil. Gondor prospered for many decades under the rule of Anárion’s line, and became the most powerful kingdom in the land, expanding its borders and conquering parts of Harad and Rhûn.\n\nBut after the return of Sauron darkness fell upon Gondor. Civil war, plague and Easterling expansions gravely weakened the once powerful Kingdom. Lands were lost to the South and East; the cities of Osgiliath and Ithilien were devasted; the tower of Minas Ithil was captured by the Nazgûl, and thereafter known as Minas Morgul. Eärnur, last King of Gondor, fell at the hands of the Witch-king, and Gondor fell into the hands of Stewards. Many years of war and instability followed. Eventually, Steward Cirion called on the Éothéod, a tribe of Northmen, for aid, and the enemy was successfully driven back. As a reward, he granted Gondor’s new allies the province of Calenardhon, where they founded the Kingdom of Rohan.\n\nNow Steward Ecthelion II rules in Gondor, and he must strengthen his realm against the threat of Mordor and its allies: the Haradrim and the Easterlings. The Pirates of Umbar cause a further threat, pillaging the Kingdom’s southern coasts. Gondor’s stability and pride hangs in the balance.\n\nThe bulk of Gondor’s army is made up of well-trained infantry and the less-experienced provincial militia. Higher ranking troops include the Fountain Guard and Ithilien archers. However, Gondor’s pride truly lies in their cavalry – few in numbers but powerful knights of Minas Tirith and Dol Amroth, capable of breaking any enemy formation. 
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_TITLE}Rohan
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_MILAN_DESCR}King Thengel \n\n\n\nThe Kingdom of Rohan was established in the Third Age, when the cavalry forces of the Kingdom of Rhovanion were destroyed by Easterlings and forced to flee beyond Greenwood the Great. These Horse People of Northmen called themselves Éothéod. They settled for some time to the north of the Anduin. In time Cirion, Steward of Gondor, called upon these descendants of Rhovanion, old allies of Gondor, for aid against the Balchoth.\n\nThus in 2510 of the Third Age, the Éothéod King Eorl the Young led his horsemen in the Battle of the Field of Celebrant, and after defeating the enemy Cirion asked the Éothéod to watch over the depopulated province of Calenardhon. The Éothéod henceforth called themselves Eorlingas or "followers of Eorl", but in Sindarin they became known as the Rohirrim, or Horse-lords, and their country became known as Rohan, the Riddermark.\n\nEorl, first King of the Mark built his capital at Aldburg in the Folde. It was Rohan's second King, Brego son of Eorl, who then established a stronghold on the green hill of Edoras at the foot of the White Mountains in the south of the Mark. At its heart stands Meduseld, the Golden Hall.\n\nDuring the time of king Helm Hammerhand around 2750, men from Dunland in the north had become hateful of the new settlers at their southern borders, who had driven them to poor lands in the hills. Now the Dunlendings came against Rohan in force under Freca and Wulf, besieging Edoras twice in four years. Pirates from Umbar were raiding Gondor and so it was unable to aid its ally in the north. The Rohirrim were forced to retreat to the fortresses of the Hornburg and Dunharrow.\n\nDuring the desperate fighting over a long winter King Helm was slain and all his sons, thus a new line of Rohirrim kings was born in Helm’s nephew – Frealaf Hildeson. Gondor eventually arrived in the spring and liberated the Riddermark from the Dunlendings.\n\nFor a time there was peace by since Saruman has settled in Isengard the folk have begun to wonder whether the terrifying wizard has had some hand in the woes that have beset the Riddermark. Dunlendings stir once more and strange creatures raiding the outer hamlets in the north have been seen bearing the dreaded White Hand of the wizard himself.
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_TITLE}Denmark
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_DENMARK_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_TITLE}Eriador
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_TURKS_DESCR}King Aragorn Elessar \n\n\n\nThe lands between the Misty Mountains and the Blue Mountains are named Eriador. In the north it is bordered by the frozen bay of Forochel and in the south by the White Mountains. Such natural defences have at times allowed the land to prosper, but it has not always been peaceful.\n\nFor in the year 3320 of the Second Age, Elendil established the Northern kingdom of Numenorians - Arnor. Elendil built many settlements here – Amnnuminas the great capital of Arnor, and fortresses such as Fornost, Amon Sul and Tarbad. There was also the high tower of Elostirion in which one of the great treasures of Middle-earth was kept the great Palantir.. Sauron hated the Dúnedain Numenorians and sought to destroy them. In the war of the Last Alliance, the Dark Lord’s forces were defeated but leaders of the Alliance against him - Elendil and Gil-galad were killed in the fighting. Isildur - son of Elendil was himself the bane of the Dark Lord and it was he that took up the One Ring. When Elendil fell and the One Ring was lost, his son Valandil became king. After the Disaster of the Gladden Fields, Arnor began its slow decline. While Gondor rose in power, Arnor waned.\n\nAfter the death of its tenth king, Eärendur, in T.A. 861, Arnor was shaken by civil war between the three sons of Eärendur. The eldest son, Amlaith, claimed Kingship over all Arnor but was reduced to only ruling the region of Arthedain as his kingdom, while the other sons founded the kingdoms of Cardolan and Rhudaur. The former capital, Annúminas, became depopulated and fell into ruin. This marked the start of the decline of the Northern Dúnedain.\n\nThe three kingdoms had frequent border skirmishes over boundary disputes, but the relationship of Arthedain and Cardolan remained relatively peaceful. However, Rhudaur was unfriendly towards the two other successor states, and took part in a bitter conflict with Cardolan over the tower of Amon Sûl and the palantír associated with the tower. Around T.A. 1300, an evil power, the Witch-king, arose in the mountains of the North East, where he founded Angmar. It was later revealed he was the leader of the Nazgûl.\n\nIn 1974 the Witch-king destroyed Fornost and with it the last of Dunedain here. One year later Angmar was defeated by Gondor and Elves but northern Kingdom of Numenorians was lost. Only a part of dunedain leading by Aradart - descendant of Isildur survived. Most of Eriador people died in wars and in time of Great Plague, last of the Dúnedain. Although some still wander in the wilderness, to all intents and purposes, Eriador has been ever since a kingdom without a king, or at least a king who would show himself to the Shadow.\n\nBut as the echoes of Sauron whisper in the world, the rallying cry has risen in the Free Lands. Aragorn II, son of Arathorn, is the last of the great Dúnedain and the burdened king of Eriador. Aragorn would seek to reforge not only the alliance of men and Elves, but also the kingdoms of Arnor reunited into a mighty whole, and perhaps even the shards of Narsil.
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_TITLE}Dwarves
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_MOORS_DESCR}King Dain \n\n\n\nAfter the destruction of the great Dwarven settlements of Nogrod and Belegost at the end of First Age, and the capturing of Khazad-dûm by the Balrog in 1980, the Dwarves fell into decay. Constant warring with Dragons and Orcs saw the loss of settlements in the Grey Mountains and Erebor. The nine-year-long War of the Dwarves and the Orcs, culminating in the bloody Battle of Azanulbizar, saw the eventual defeat of the Orcs, but brought with it severe repercussions, threatening the Dwarves’ very existence.\n\nOnly in the year 2941, after Bard the Bowman slew the dragon Smaug, did the Dwarves at last regain hope. Allying with the Men of Dale and Mirkwood Elves, they won the Battle of Five Armies, reclaiming the Lonely Mountain. Dwarves of the Iron Hills, led by Dáin Ironfoot, resettled Erebor and started the tiresome resurrection of a tattered nation.\n\nWith the Northern Goblins weak and scattered, it is a great opportunity to regain native lands. Moreover Balin, one of the great Dwarven princes, has sworn to return to Khazad-dûm and muster troops for the campaign to reclaim Moria. And to the South, the Men of Dale have proven to be our loyal allies; we can always count on them for help.\n\nDwarven armies consist mostly of heavy infantry. Armed with axes and battle-hammers, they are deadly at short range. When it comes to armour, the Dwarves’ skill in forging steel and mithril is unmatched. Further, the Dwarven reputation as master engineers allows them some of the finest siege weapons, and gives them access to the crossbow. Their alliance with Dale allows them to hire some basic Northman units, making up for their lack of cavalry.
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_TITLE}Poland
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_POLAND_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_TITLE}Byzantium
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_BYZANTIUM_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_TITLE}Hungary
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_HUNGARY_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_TITLE}Russia
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_RUSSIA_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_AZTECS_TITLE}The Aztecs
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_AZTECS_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_TITLE}Harad
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_SPAIN_DESCR}Chieftain Khuzaymah \n\n\n\nFor the lands beyond the River Harnen the men of Gondor give no name other than Harad -- the South -- and to the proud and warlike people who dwell there they give no label other than Haradrim -- Men of the South. These are descendants of men who fell under the sway of Morgoth during the First Age and who rallied to the banners of Sauron in the Second Age.\n\nLong have the Haradrim been at odds with the men of Gondor, and often have the borders between the two realms been redrawn due to war and conquest. In the year 1050 of the Third Age, King Ciryaher utterly vanquished the armies of the Haradrim and compelled their kings to accept the authority of Gondor, a feat that won him the name Hyarmendacil -- Victor of the South.\n\nThe supremacy of Gondor was short-lived, however, for barely four centuries later, a dispute over succession threw Gondor into civil war. As a result of the Kin-strife, the sons of Castamir the Usurper departed Gondor with the bulk of the fleet anchored at Pelargir and established themselves in the ancient Númenórian haven of Umbar. What hold Gondor held over the Haradrim was lost, and many alliances were forged between the rebels -- now known as the Corsairs of Umbar -- and the men of Harad. In the years since, the two peoples have perpetuated war against Gondor, terrorizing the coasts and contesting control over the lands of southern territories of Harondor.\n\nWhile the men who march under the serpent banner of Harad cannot hope to match the craft of Gondor in the smithing of weapons and armor, the armies of Harad are vast, their spears sharp, and their steeds swift. Furthermore, in the lands to the north, rumors abound of mûmakil, great tusked beasts of war coaxed from the jungles of the Far Harad that are all but unstoppable in battle. With such weapons at their disposal and allied with the forces of Mordor resurgent the Haradrim may yet see final triumph over their ancient foe to the north.
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_TITLE}Remnants of Angmar
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_PORTUGAL_DESCR}Chieftain Gorduf \n\n\n\nDO NOT TRANSLATE
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_TITLE}The Dark Lord of Mordor
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_PAPAL_STATES_DESCR}DO NOT TRANSLATE
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_TITLE}Silvan Elves
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_MONGOLS_DESCR}King Thranduil \n\n\n\nDoriath, the Hidden Kingdom, was the greatest of the Sindarin realms in Beleriand. For many long years, it flourished under the rule of Elu Thingol and Melian his queen, but during the Wars of Beleriand it was destroyed, sacked first by treacherous dwarves and later by the jealous Sons of Fëanor. Many of those who survived the fall of the realm fled east past the towering peaks of the Hithaeglir into lands where the Tawarwaith -- Silvan elves long sundered from the elves of Beleriand -- dwelled.\n\nBeing a rustic people lesser in wisdom than the Sindar, the Silvan elves accepted the Sindar as their lords. Under the guidance of Amdír and Oropher, the realms of Lindórinand and Eryn Lasgalen were established, and for many years the elves lived in peace. Peace, however, was not to last, for the rising power of Mordor forced the Silvan elves and their Sindarin princes to take up arms. During the Last Alliance of Elves and Men, Amdír and Oropher, along with their sons Amroth and Thranduil, heeded the call Gil-galad and led great hosts to battle. Sauron was defeated, but at great cost -- both Amdír and Oropher were slain, along with most of their armies.\n\nHis heart filled with disquiet and disillusionment, Thranduil led his people northwards, where he established his Woodland Realm and delved an underground fortress in the style of Menegroth in Doriath. In Lindórinand, now known as Lothlórien, Amroth took over the lordship of his father's kingdom. After Amroth was lost at sea searching for his beloved, the Silvan maiden Nimrodel, Celeborn and Galadriel took up the guardianship of the realm, fortifying it against the resurgent power of Mordor.\n\nUnder the guidance of the Lord and Lady of the Wood, the realm of Lothlórien shines in defiance of the shadow growing in the East, a fortress against the encroaching darkness. And while the Silvan elves of Lórien and the Woodland Realm may be ill-equipped in arms and armor when compared to their western kin, they are hardy and valiant warriors whose skill with the bow is unmatched and whose hatred of Sauron runs deep. 
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_TITLE}The Fellowship
{FELLOWSHIP_CAMPAIGN_TIMURIDS_DESCR}Frodo Baggins, a hobbit from the Shire, is the son of Drogo Baggins and Primula Brandybuck. At the age of 12, Frodo lost both his parents in a boating accident and was taken in by his maternal family, the Brandybuck clan. At 21, Frodo was adopted by Bilbo Baggins. During the next 12 years, Bilbo taught Frodo much of the Elvish language, and they often shared long walking trips together.\n\nBilbo is celebrating his 111th birthday on the same day that Frodo Baggins, his heir, is celebrating his 33rd birthday (his 'coming of age'). At the birthday party, Bilbo disappears after his speech, to the surprise of all. Bilbo departs from the Shire, the land of the Hobbits, for what he calls a permanent holiday. He leaves his remaining belongings including his home, Bag End and, after some persuasion by the wizard Gandalf, the Ring he had found on his adventures (with which he used to make himself invisible), to Frodo. Gandalf warns Frodo to keep the Ring secret and safe from others, and leaves on his own business.\n\nOver the next seventeen years Gandalf visits Frodo; staying briefly before going off again. Then one spring night Gandalf arrives to alert Frodo to the darker aspects of the Ring which Bilbo had previously only used to make himself invisible: it is the One Ring of Sauron, the Dark Lord. Sauron forged the Ring himself and used it to subdue and rule Middle-earth. In the War of the Last Alliance, Sauron was defeated by the Elven King Gil-galad and Elendil, High King of Gondor and Arnor, though they themselves perished in the deed. The Ring was cut off from Sauron by Isildur, son of Elendil. Sauron was thus overthrown and he fled, and so, for many years, peace returned to Middle-earth. But the Ring itself was not destroyed: Isildur kept the Ring for himself after cutting it from Sauron. However, Isildur was slain in the Battle of the Gladden Fields and the Ring was lost in the Great River, Anduin; whereupon it came into the hands of the creature Gollum, who possessed the Ring for many years. The Ring then passed to Bilbo Baggins and so passes into the hands of Frodo.\n\nSauron had now arisen once again, and had returned to his stronghold in the land of Mordor, and was exerting all his power to find the Ring. Gandalf details the evil powers of the Ring, and its ability to influence the bearer and those near him, if it is worn for too long a time. Gandalf warns that the Ring is no longer safe in the Shire because, after some investigation of his own, he has learned from Gollum himself that Gollum had gone to Mordor, where he was captured and was tortured into revealing to Sauron that a Hobbit named Baggins from the Shire possesses the Ring. Heeding Gandalf's advice, Frodo decides that it is best to remove the Ring from the Shire.\n\nNote: The Fellowship can only be played on Very Hard campaign difficulty.
